Vladyslav Parkhomenko

(+1) 438-497-5062 | avgona2017@yahoo.com | <a href="mailto:display:150%] https://github.com/Avgonal

Summary

Java Developer with experience in Back-end development in monolith and microservice architecture, lover JVM languages such as Java, Scala and Groovy. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience

DahliaMatic Warszawa, Poland

Java Developer

Nov. 2021 - Oct. 2022

- Implemented different API microservices from the scratch for Polish governmental application to control investments in properties under construction.
- Built whole JMS communication in project using to process JSON and file huge requests asynchronously, it allowed us to speed up processing data from 12 to 3 seconds.
- Built generics mechanism that can process all 18 types of requests, validate them, persist files and data, it let us to save 1 month development.
- Implemented OpenStackApi Storage to keep our BLOB files and taught how to use such API more than 10 people from other projects.

Immotef Warszawa, Poland Java Developer May. 2021 - Nov. 2022

- Implemented more than 60% of RESTful API server in monolith architecture for examining water for bacteria application.
- Implemented JWT authorization with different roles, authorities based on their subscription and country of registration.
- Built overall NoSQL communication with MongoDB and CosmosDB in Azure Cloud including consumption of Azure File Storage to persist data from water sensors.
- Covered 60% the project with unit and integration tests it allowed us to catch lots a errors on the middle and final stage.

Internship Warszawa, Poland FullStack Developer Feb. 2021 - May. 2021

Implemented 30% of RESTful API in social media application.

Helped to build front-end part in HTML, SCSS, JS, ChartJS

Skills

- Language: Java 11, Scala
- Framework: Spring (Core, Boot, MVC, REST, DATA, Cache, Security, AOP), JMS, Hibernate
- Database: MySQL, OracleDB, MongoDB, CosmosDB
- Libraries: Jackson, Lombok, MapStruct, Liquibase
- Test: JUnit 5, Mockito, TestContainers
- Front-End: HTML, CSS, JS, ChartJS, Thymeleaf
- **Documentation**: Swagger OpenAPI3, Confluence, Enterprise Architect
- Other tools: AWS, Docker, Git, GitHub, BitBucket, GitLab, Maven, Gradle, Trello, Jira

Education

University of Banking Wroclaw, Poland **B.S. IN Computer Science** 2018 - 2021

Specialization: Application Cloud Developer

NUTCAC

Courses	
Udemy – Spring Boot & Hibernate for Beginners	2020
Udemy – Spring framework 5: Beginner to Guru	2021
Udemy – Advanced Hibernate	2021
Udemy - Spring Boot unit testing with Junit, Mockito and MockMVC	2022
Udemy – JMS – Java Message Services	2022
Udemy – Scala at light speed	2022